const qBank = [
	{
		id: 1,
		question: "Which one of the following planets has largest number of natural satellites or moons?",
		options: ["Jupiter", "Mars", "Saturn", "Venus"],
		answer: "Saturn",
	},
	{
		id: 2,
		question: "Among the following which planet takes maximum time for one revolution around the Sun?",
		options: ["Earth", "Venus", "Mars", "Jupiter"],
		answer: "Jupiter",
	},
	{
		id: 3,
		question: " A “Black Hole “is a body in space which does not allow any radiation to come out. This property is due to its",
		options: ["Very small size", "Very high density", "Very large size", "Very low density"],
		answer: "Very high density"
	},
	{
		id: 4,
		question: "One Astronomical Unit is the average distance between ____________.",
		options: ["Earth and the Sun", "Jupiter and the Sun", "Pluto and the Sun", "Earth and the Moon"],
		answer: "Earth and the Sun"
	},
	{
		id: 5,
		question: "Who among the following proposed Helio-centric model of solar system?",
		options: ["Copernicus", "Ptolemy", "Aristotle", "Strabo"],
		answer: "Copernicus"
	},
	{
		id: 6,
		question: "Which one of the following planet is also called morning star or evening star?",
		options: ["Mercury", "Venus", "Mars", "Saturn"],
		answer: "Venus"
	},
    {
		id: 7,
		question: "The device employed to measure the diameters of stars and our galaxy (Milky Way) is called:",
		options: ["Photometer", "Barometer", "Viscometer", "Interferometer"],
		answer: "Interferometer"
	},
	
	{
		id: 8,
		question: "The planet(s) with no moons is/are",
		options: ["Venus and Mars", "Mars and Neptune", "Mercury and Mars", "Mercury and Venus"],
		answer: "Mercury and Venus"
	},
	{
		id: 9,
		question: "The position of a planet when it is nearest to the Sun is called",
		options: ["Apogee", "Aphelion", "Perigee", "Perihelion"],
		answer: "Perihelion"
	},
	{
		id: 10,
		question: "The unit of measuring distances between the stars is known as____________________.",
		options: ["Light year", "Stellar mile", "Cosmic kilometer", "Galactic unit"],
		answer: "Light year"
	},
	{
		id: 11,
		question: "On which of the following planets of the solar system does the sun rise in the west and set in the east?",
		options: ["Saturn", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Venus"],
		answer: "Venus"
	},
	{
		id: 12,
		question: "Which one of the following planets takes the same number of days for rotation and revolution?",
		options: ["Mercury", "Mars", "Jupiter", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Mercury"
	},
	{
		id: 13,
		question: "Nearest star to the earth is _____.",
		options: ["Sun", "Proxima Centaury", "Alfa Centaury", "Dog Star"],
		answer: "Sun"
	},
	{
		id: 14,
		question: "Sun-rays reaches earth in (approximately)",
		options: [" 8 seconds", "8 minutes", "4.3 seconds", "1 light year"],
		answer: "8 minutes"
	},
	{
		id: 15,
		question: "A system of millions and millions of galaxies are called _____.",
		options: ["Universe", "Solar System", "Constellation", "Space"],
		answer: "Universe"
	},
	{
		id: 16,
		question: "The name of our galaxy is _______",
		options: ["Alfa Centauri", "Milky Way", "Proxima Centauri", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Milky Way"
	},
	{
		id: 17,
		question: "Big Bang Theory' explains ________ .",
		options: ["The formation of universe", "The origin and evolution of earth's crust", "Formation of Solar System", "Formation of constellation"],
		answer: "The formation of universe"
	},
	{
		id: 18,
		question: "Who is the father of modern space science in India?",
		options: ["APJ Abdula Kalam", "Vikram Sarabhai", "Satish Dhawan", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Vikram Sarabhai"
	},
	{
		id: 19,
		question: "In order for a solar eclipse to occur, the Moon must be",
		options: ["near new Moon", "near first or last quarter", "near full Moon", " high in the sky"],
		answer: "near new Moon"
	},
	{
		id: 20,
		question: "The outermost layer of Sun is called",
		options: ["Corona", "Chromosphere", "Photosphere", "Lithosphere"],
		answer: "Corona"
	},
	{
		id: 21,
		question: "What causes the change of seasons?",
		options: [" Earth’s rotation and inclination of its axis", "Earth’s revolution and inclination of its axis", "Earth’s revolution", "Earth’s rotation and revolution"],
		answer: "Earth’s revolution and inclination of its axis"
	},
	{
		id: 22,
		question: "By how much degree the earth is inclined on its own axis",
		options: [" 24 1/2°", "69 1/2°", "66 1/2°", "23 1/2°"],
		answer: "23 1/2°"
	},
	{
		id: 23,
		question: "The sun is veritical over the Tropic of Cancer on",
		options: ["Sept. 23", "Dec. 22", "March 21", "June 21"],
		answer: "June 21"
	},
	{
		id: 24,
		question: "On which date is the earth in perihelion?",
		options: ["January 3", "July 4", "Dec 22", "June 21"],
		answer: "January 3"
	},
	{
		id: 25,
		question: "Space between Earth and Moon is known as_________________ .",
		options: ["Nebula", "Cislunar", "Fulalunar", "None of these"],
		answer: "Cislunar"
	},
]

export default qBank;
